Herbert A. Philbrick Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- I Led 3 Lives, 1940-1972 (Box 13-28)
  - Television
    - Scripts
      - No. 114, "Heart Attack," Jan.-Feb. 1956
      - No. 115, "Eva Purged," Jan.-Mar. 1956
      - No. 116, "Student Contest,” Feb.-Mar. 1956, (2 folders)
      - No. 117, "Commie Son," Feb.-Mar. 1956 (Box 28)
      - Unidentified, 1954, undated
- Subject File, 1849-1997 (Box 28-221)
  Correspondence, memoranda, newsletters, reports, newspaper clippings, notes, pamphlets, and other printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization, person, or topic.
  - Abel, Rudolph Ivanovich, 1958-1971, undated (Box 28)
  - Abernathy, Ralph D., 1968-1971
  - Abortion, 1970-1974, 1984-1994, undated, (2 folders)
  - Abt, John J., 1967-1969, undated
  - Accuracy in Media (AIM), 1968-1992, undated, (2 folders)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1964-1968, undated
  - Adams, James Luther, 1955-1959
  - Adams, Sherman, 1953-1955
  - Adamson, Lee S., 1967-1983, undated
  - Adventurers' Club of New York, 1954-1973, undated
  - Advertising, 1952, 1967, undated (Box 29)
  - Afghanistan, 1957-1959, 1979, 1985-1990
  - Africa, 1957-1971, undated
  - Agnew, Spiro T., 1968-1974, undated
  - AIDS (disease), 1990, undated
  - Air Force manual, 1960, (2 folders)
  - Albania, 1961-1973, 1986-1991, undated
  - Albanian Orthodox Church, 1965
  - Aleksander, Irina, 1949, undated
  - Alert American Association, 1957-1964, undated
  - Alexander, Shana, 1965-1966
  - Alger, Bruce, 1963-1966, undated
  - Algeria, 1962-1965, undated
  - Alinsky, Saul D., 1962-1972, undated
  - All-American Conference to Combat Communism, 1950-1968, undated, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 30)
  - Allen-Bradley Co., 1958-1959, undated
  - Allen, Paul C., 1958-1970
  - Allen, Steve, 1959-1968, undated
  - Alliance, Inc., 1955-1957
  - Alliluyeva, Svetlana Stalin, 1967-1972, 1979, 1985, undated
  - Alps, Vlademar, undated
  - Alsop, Joseph, 1958-1966, undated
  - American-African Affairs Association, 1965-1968, undated
  - American Artists Professional League, 1956-1961, undated (Box 31)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1956-1967, undated
  - American Association of University Women, 1954-1955
  - American Baptist Convention, 1954-1972, undated, (3 folders)
  - American Bar Association, 1958-1966
  - American Book Co., 1958, 1964-1967
  - American Center for Education, 1968-1970
  - American China Policy Association, 1959-1960
  - American Christian Palestine Association, 1953-1959
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1952-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies, 1954-1962, 1973, undated
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1954-1956
  - American Committee for Liberation, 1957-1962, undated, (4 folders)
  - American Committee on Africa, 1957-1958, undated
  - American Committee to Free Cuba, 1963-1966, undated
  - American Conservative Union, 1965-1976, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 33)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1951-1957, undated, (2 folders)
  - American Council for World Freedom, 1969-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - American Council of Christian Churches, 1953-1958, 1966, undated
  - American Council on Germany, 1959-1961
  - American Economic Foundation, 1960, 1966-1967, undated
  - American Education Lobby, 1970, undated
  - American Farm Bureau Federation, 1953-1966, undated
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, 1959-1960
  - American Forum for Socialist Education, 1957 (Box 34)
  - American Federation for the Preservation of the Christian Heritage, 1947-1958, undated, (4 folders)
  - American Friends of Anti-Bolshevist Bloc of Nations, 1957, undated
  - American Friends of Russian Freedom, 1952-1959
  - American Friends of Captive Nations, 1958-1968
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1953-1969, undated, (3 folders)
  - American Heritage Foundation, 1954-1963 (Box 35)
  - American Institute, 1959-1963, undated, (3 folders)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1953-1956, 1964
  - American-Korean Friendship and Information Center, 1971
  - American Legion
    - Firing Line, 1952-1972, 1981, undated, (3 folders); (6 folders) (Box 36)
    - Massachusetts, 1948-1958, undated
    - Miscellany, 1936, 1952-1968, 1982, undated
    - National Americanism Commission, 1952-1960, 1966-1967, undated, (6 folders) (Box 37)
    - New York, 1952-1964, 1970, 1984, undated, (3 folders)
  - American Lobby, undated
  - American Mercury, 1953-1965, undated
  - American Mothers Committee, 1955-1957, undated
  - American Nazi Party, 1959-1972, undated
  - American Opinion, 1960, 1967-1969, 1984, undated
  - American Opinion Speakers Bureau, 1962-1963, undated
  - American Security Council, 1957-1979, 1985, undated, (7 folders) (Box 38)
  - American Town Halls, Inc., 1952-1955, undated, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 39)
  - American Veterans for Peace, 1952
  - American Youth Congress, 1940-1951, undated For additional material see Containers 9-12, Party activities
  - American Youth for Democracy, 1943-1947, undated For additional material see Containers 9-12, Party activities, (2 folders)
  - Americanism Educational League, 1961-1970, undated
  - Americans for Conservative Action, 1963-1967
  - Americans for Constitutional Action, 1959-1965, undated
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1950-1965, undated
  - America's Future
    - “Behind the Headlines” broadcasts, 1958-1959, 1983-1993, (4 folders); (13 folders); (1 folder) (Box 40, Box 41)
    - General, 1958-1993, undated, (9 folders); (10 folders) (Box 42)
    - Newsletter, 1959-1991, (7 folders) (Box 43)
    - Pamphlets, 1956-1985, undated, (3 folders)
    - Textbook Evaluation Committee, 1958-1980, undated, (6 folders) (Box 44)
  - Amnesty, 1972-1974, undated
  - Amoss, Ulius L., 1959-1961
  - AMVETS, 1958-1959, undated
  - Amway, 1974-1977, undated
  - Anderson, Charles J., 1962-1970, undated
  - Anderson, Clinton P., 1957, undated
  - Anderson, Jack, 1968-1972, 1983-1986 (Box 45)
  - Andover Newton Theological Seminary, Newton Centre, Mass., 1960-1963
  - Andrews, T. Coleman, 1959
  - Angers, Bob, Jr., 1966-1967, undated
  - Anglo-American relations, 1957, 1963
  - Angola, 1961-1964, 1976, 1989, undated, (3 folders)
  - Anti-ballistic missile (ABM), 1967-1969, undated
  - Antibolshevik Bloc of Nations, 1958, 1967
  - Anticommunism school, 1958-1965, 1971-1977, undated
  - Anticommunist book burning, 1955-1956
  - Anticommunist pamphlets and fliers, 1951-1968, undated, (6 folders) (Box 46)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai Brith, 1950-1970, undated, (3 folders)
  - Anti-nukes, 1975-1988, undated (Box 47)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1951-1973, 1979, undated, (4 folders)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 1952-1954, 1964-1969
  - Arab Information Center, 1956-1969, undated, (4 folders)
  - Arens, Richard, 1957-1960
  - Argentina, 1957, 1967-1974, undated
  - Argue, John S., 1964-1972 (Box 48)
  - Armenia, 1953-1972, undated
  - Armenian Revolutionary Committee, 1955-1965, undated
  - Armenian Weekly, 1967-1976, undated
  - Arnold, Melvin, 1952-1960, undated
  - Aron, Paul Harvey, 1953
  - Aronson, Allan James, 1953-1954
  - Art, 1952-1963, undated, (2 folders)
  - Arts and science professions, 1949-1952, undated
  - Artukovic, Andrija, 1958
  - Ashbrook, John M., 1962-1976
  - Asbrook, William E., 1960-1963
  - Asia, 1951, 1960-1967, undated
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations, 1955-1967, 1975, undated, (3 folders) (Box 49)
  - Association of Sons and Daughters of Cherokee Strip Pioneers, 1959-1970
  - Atheists, 1963, 1971, 1988
  - Attitude Research Laboratory, St. Louis, Mo., 1956
  - Austin Anti-Communism League, Austin, Tex., 1960-1966, (2 folders)
  - Australian League of Rights, 1947-1971, undated, (3 folders) (Box 50)
  - AWARE, Inc., 1953-1961
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1936, 1949-1979, 1986-1992, undated, (3 folders)
  - Baarslag, Karl, 1954-1964, undated
  - Bacon, Leslie, 1971
  - Baez, Joan, 1966-1972, undated
  - Baha'i Faith, 1951, 1968-1969, undated (Box 51)
  - Bailey, Harold C., 1959-1960
  - Baker, Bobby, 1964-1972
  - Baker, Catherine M., 1953-1954, undated
  - Baland, Arnold, 1963-1970
  - Baldwin, Roger, 1958, 1968
  - Bales, James D. For additional material see Containers 222-223, “The Communist Attack on Religion”
    - General, 1951-1987, 1993-1997, undated, (7 folders); (4 folders) (Box 52)
    - Writings, 1959-1967, 1987-1989, undated, (5 folders); (7 folders); (1 folder) (Box 53, Box 54)
  - Balinky, Alexander S., 1955-1957, undated, (4 folders)
  - Ball, George W., 1966-1969
  - Ball, Lee H., 1966, undated
  - Ball, Luella, 1 963-1971, 1977-1978, undated
  - Baltic Review, 1953-1955, undated
  - Baltic states, 1952-1968, 1975, undated
  - Bang-Jensen, Povl, 1958-1963, undated
  - Baptist Convention of New England, 1986-1989
  - Baptist Joint Committee on Public Affairs, 1973-1976, (2 folders)
  - Baptist-Russian relations, 1954-1956, undated (Box 55)
  - Baptist study of communism, 1960, undated
  - Baptist World Alliance, 1955-1958, 1975-1976
  - Barnes, E. Richard, 1960-1972, undated
  - Barnes, Joseph, 1937-1939, 1949-1956, 1970, 1977, undated
  - Barry M. Goldwater Republican Club, Jackson Heights, N. Y., 1968-1969
  - Bartholomew, Fletcher, 1958
  - Bay Area Network Development Program, Northern California, 1966
  - Beekeeping, 1971-1974, undated
  - Beezley, P. C., 1962-1972, undated
  - Bell, Allyn R., Jr., 1960-1969, undated
  - Bell, Don, 1957-1959
  - Bennett, John C., 1957-1966
  - Benson, George S., 1955-1972, 1991, undated
  - Bentley, Elizabeth, 1953, undated
  - Bernatschke, Rudolf, 1944, undated
  - Berrigan, Daniel and Philip, 1971-1972, undated
  - Bethel, Paul, 1969-1971
  - Biafra, 1968-1969, undated
  - Bialer, Seweryn, undated
  - Bialoguski, Michael, 1956-1959, undated
  - Bicentennial of the American Revolution (Box 56)
    - Baptist Church activities, 1969-1976, undated
    - General, 1969-1976, undated
    - People's Bicentennial Commission, 1975-1976, undated
  - Bill of Rights (Laws), 1963, undated
  - Billings, Roger, 1958-1974, 1995-1997, undated
  - Bingham, Barry, 1963-1965
  - Bishop, Jim (1907-1987), 1961-1964, undated
  - Black, Algernon D., 1955-1956, undated
  - Black, J. Thomas, 1969-1972
  - Black Panther Party, 1968-1972, undated, (3 folders)
  - Black power, 1967-1970, undated
  - Blacklisting, 1954-1959
  - Blake, Eugene Carson, 1956-1958, 1966, undated
  - Blanco, Ernesto E., 1969
  - Blomberg, William Frary von, 1960-1983, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 57)
  - Blumit, Oswald A., 1953-1970, undated
  - Blythe, Shelton M., 1965-1970, undated
  - Bob Jones University, Greenville, S. C., 1968-1971
  - Boldug, Hector L., 1968
  - Boldyreff, Constantin W., 1959-1971, undated
  - Bombings, 1969-1970
  - Book lists, undated
  - Book publishers
    - Acropolis Books, 1971-1972, undated
    - Beacon Press, 1952-1959
    - Caxton Printers, 1954-1956, 1968-1972, undated
    - Columbia Books, 1968-1969, undated
    - Crestwood Books, 1966-1967, undated
    - Devin-Adair Co., 1957-1965, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1951, 1957-1971, undated, (2 folders)
  - Bookmailer, 1955-1973, undated, (3 folders) (Box 58)
  - Books
    - Communist, 1951-1952, 1959, 1968, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-1969, 1976, 1991, undated, (2 folders)
  - Boston Public Library, Boston, Mass., 1948-1958
  - Boston Tea Party, undated
  - Boudin, Leonard B., 1948, 1955, 1964-1972
  - Bouscaren, Anthony T., 1961-1967, undated
  - Bowditch, E. Francis, 1957-1961, undated
  - Bowdre, J. B., 1963 (Box 59)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1956-1971
  - Bozyk, Monika, 1957, undated
  - Braden, Carl and Anne, 1953-1959
  - Braden, Spruille, 1953-1960, 1967-1970
  - Brainwashing
    - General, 1954-1969, undated, (2 folders)
    - In high schools, 1957-1959, undated
  - Brandt, Willy, 1970-1971, undated
  - Brazil, 1960-1969
  - Breshnan, Thomas H., 1957-1958
  - Bretz, Theodore, 1967
  - Brewer, Roy M., 1951, 1960-1967
  - Brezhnev, Leonid I., 1965-1978, undated
  - Bridges, Harry, 1958-1959
  - Bridges, Styles, 1958-1963
  - Brown, H. Rap, 1967-1973, undated
  - Brown, Julia Clarice, 1966, undated
  - Browne, Benjamin P., 1953
  - Brownfeld, Allan C., 1968-1972, undated
  - Browning, Harry, 1956
  - Bruce, Donald C., 1958-1966, undated (Box 60)
  - Bruno's Research Digest, 1970-1972
  - Buchanan, Patrick J., 1984-1990, undated
  - Buck, Pearl S., 1959, 1970-1973
  - Buckley, William F. (1925- ), 1958-1975, 1983, undated
  - Buddhism, 1956, 1966
  - Budenz, Louis F., 1948-1951, 1958-1960, 1972, undated
  - Bulgaria, 1955, 1965, undated
  - Bunche, Ralph J., 1954-1957, 1964, undated
  - Bundy, Edgar C., 1952-1967, undated, (2 folders)
  - Burger, Henry G., 1962
  - Burgess, Guy, 1959-1965
  - Burgum, Edwin Berry, 1953, undated
  - Burke, Albert E., 1961-1962
  - Burnes, Vincent Godfrey, 1968-1970
  - Business Builders, 1979-1982, undated
  - Browder, Earl, 1950, 1960, 1973, undated
  - Byfield, Robert S., 1949-1959, undated
  - “B” miscellaneous, 1933, 1949-1975, 1989-1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 61)
  - Caldicott, Helen, 1980-1984, undated
  - Californian, 1961-1962
  - Cambodia, 1966-1979, 1989, undated
  - Cameron, Angus, 1948-1953, undated
  - Campbell, Carleton, 1965
  - Camps, 1952-1957, undated
  - Campus Crusade for Christ, 1969-1970, undated
  - Campus demonstrations, disorder, and violence, 1965-1969
  - Campus World, Inc., 1961-1962, undated
  - Canada, 1944, 1953-1972, undated
  - Canwell, Albert F., 1954-1971, (2 folders)
  - Capitalism, 1956-1958, 1966
  - Captive nations lists, 1960, 1966-1967, 1977, 1987-1989, undated (Box 62)
  - Captive Nations Week, 1960-1986, undated, (3 folders)
  - Caradja, Catherine, 1966, 1973, undated
  - Cardinal Mindszenty Foundation, 1959-1984, undated, (6 folders)
  - Carlson, Richard, 1955, 1963-1968, 1977 (Box 63)
  - Carmichael, Stokely, 1966-1972, undated
  - Castro, Fidel, 1959-1971, 1985, (2 folders)
  - Catania, Peter, 1970-1991, undated
  - Catholic Fact Research Association, 1964, undated
  - Catholics
    - Anti-Catholicism, 1954-1962, undated
    - General, 1937, 1956-1966, undated
  - Celler, Emanuel, 1959
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1961, 1968
  - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), 1963-1975, undated
  - Chaing Kai-shek, 1957-1970
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1960-1966
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1952-1953, 1961, 1969, 1987, undated
  - Chase, Homer B., 1955-1958, undated
  - Chautauqua Institution, Chautauqua, N. Y., 1956-1957
  - Chavez, Cesar, 1969-1970
  - Chicago Seven, 1968-1971, undated (Box 64)
  - Chile, 1962-1979, undated, (2 folders)
  - China
    - Red China, 1954-1992, undated, (5 folders); (4 folders) (Box 65)
    - Taiwan, 1963-1976, undated, (2 folders)
  - Chinese Christian Church of New England, 1964
  - Chow, Ching-wen, 1967-1972, undated
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade For additional material see Containers 243-246, Speaking Engagements
    - 1956-1962, (2 folders)
    - 1963-1982, (9 folders) (Box 66)
    - 1983-1992, undated, (7 folders) (Box 67)
  - Christian Beacon, 1959-1967
  - Christian Cause, 1973, undated
  - Christian Century, 1955-1959, 1966
  - Christian Citizen, 1961-1962, undated
  - Christian Democratic Review, 1956-1961, (3 folders) (Box 68)
  - Christian Freedom Foundation, 1952-1972, (3 folders)
  - Christian Herald, 1953-1967, undated
  - Christian Heritage Center, Louisville, Ky., 1968-1980
  - Christian Peace Conference, 1960-1974, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 69)
  - Christian Register, 1952-1956
  - Christian Solidarity International, 1981-1983, undated
  - Christianity and communism, 1949, 1959-1965, undated
  - Christianity Today, 1959-1967, undated, (2 folders)
  - The Christophers, 1952-1972, undated
  - Church and State, 1966
  - Church League of America, 1956-1980, undated, (2 folders); (7 folders) (Box 70)
  - Church pornography, 1960-1965, undated
  - Churches
    - Communism in churches, 1944-1973, undated, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 71)
    - Miscellany, 1929, 1953-1972, 1983, undated
  - Churchman, 1949-1959, undated
  - Cinema Educational Guild, 1956-1970, undated
  - Circuit Riders, circa 1952-1967, undated, (4 folders) (Box 72)
  - Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba, 1966-1971, undated
  - Citizens Conference for International Economic Union, 1955, undated
  - Citizens' Councils of America, 1907, 1954-1958, 1964, undated
  - Citizens Emergency Defense Conference, 1952, undated
  - Citizens for a Free Kuwait, 1990-1991, undated, (2 folders)
  - Citizens for Decent Literature, 1959-1972, undated (Box 73)
  - Citizens for Educational Freedom, 1960-1971, undated
  - Citizens for Freedom, 1963-1970, undated
  - Citizens Foreign Aid Committee, 1959, undated
  - Civil Defense, 1958-1964, undated
  - Civil Rights, 1952-1971, undated
  - Clark, Joseph S., 1966, undated
  - Clark, Ramsey, 1889, 1920, 1964-1970, undated
  - Cleaver, Eldridge, 1968-1976, undated
  - Clergy, 1951-1966, undated, (5 folders)
  - Clergymen's Committee on China, 1966-1972 (Box 74)
  - Cleveland, James C., 1967-1969, undated
  - Clifford, Clark, 1954, undated
  - Clinton, Bill, 1992-1993, undated
  - Cloward, Donald B., 1954, undated
  - Coast Guard, 1970
  - Coffman, Dorothy, 1968-1974, undated
  - Colbert, James D., 1970, 1979, undated
  - Coleman, Arthur P., 1948-1953, undated
  - Colleges, 1953-1970, 1989, undated, (2 folders)
  - Collier, Franklin P., 1954-1958
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS), 1959-1960, 1967-1976
  - Columbia Lecture Bureau, 1951-1963, undated For additional material see Containers 238-239, Lecture bureaus
  - Columbia University, New York, N. Y., 1952-1954, 1968-1969, undated
  - Columbus Printing, 1965-1973, undated, (2 folders)
  - Colorado Seven, 1955-1959, undated (Box 75)
  - Combat, 1969-1970, undated
  - Commager, Henry Steele, 1962-1968, undated
  - Committee against Summit Entanglements, 1959
  - Committee for a Free China, 1972-1974
  - Committee for Nonviolent Action, 1960-1967
  - Committee of One Million, 1958-1971, undated
  - Committee to End Aid to the Soviet Enemy (CEASE), 1967-1968
  - Committee to Restore the Constitution, undated
  - Common Cause, 1956-1960, 1971-1974, undated
  - Common Sense, 1956-1972, (3 folders)
  - Commonweal, 1962-1964, 1974
  - Communications Research Services, 1969-1973, undated, (4 folders) (Box 76)
  - Communism, 1948-1976, 1989-1991, undated, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 77)
  - Communist conspiracy, 1951-1959, undated
  - Communist front organizations, 1948, 1956-1959, 1967, undated
  - Communist infiltration into communications, 1960-1961
  - Communist International, 1928, 1952-1972, undated, (3 folders)
  - Communist Manifesto, 1948, 1961-1965, 1978 (Box 78)
  - Communist Party of the Soviet Union, 1920-1922, 1952-1960, 1971, 1986, undated
  - Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA), 1936-1973, 1979, 1987-1991, undated, (9 folders)
  - Communist tactics, 1936, 1947, 1956-1959, undated
  - Community Church of Boston, Boston, Mass., 1951-1961, undated (Box 79)
  - Conference of American Small Business Associations, 1958-1959
  - Congo, 1959-1970, undated
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1956-1957
  - Congress of Freedom, 1954-1960, 1970, undated
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), 1964-1968, undated
  - Congressional reapportionment, 1964
  - Congressional Record, 1950-1972, (4 folders)
  - Conner, Stuart W., 1955-1971, undated
  - Conner, Troy B., 1956-1958
  - Conservative Book Club, 1964-1967 (Box 80)
  - Conservative Caucus, 1976-1977, undated
  - Conservatives, 1960-1971, 1977, undated
  - Constitutions, 1960-1967, 1973, undated
  - Constructive Action, 1966-1993, undated, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 81)
  - Consumers Union of the United States, 1936-1964, 1972, undated, (3 folders)
  - Contacts, 1954-1963, undated, (2 folders)
  - Continuing Committee on Muslim-Christian Cooperation, 1958-1963
  - Controversialist Newsletter, 1953-1956, undated (Box 82)
  - Cooperstock, Henry, 1957, undated
  - Coplon, Judith, 1949, 1957, 1967, undated
  - Cotton, Norris, 1960-1973, undated
  - Council Against Communist Aggression, 1954-1979, undated, (5 folders)
  - Council for Statehood, undated
  - Council for the Defense of Freedom, 1979-1993, undated
  - Council on Christian Social Progress, 1954, 1960-1961, undated
  - Council on Educational Needs, 1957-1961
  - Counterattack, 1949-1961
  - Court of World Public Opinion, International Communism on Trial, 1968 See also Container 219, same heading (Box 83)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1952-1961, 1972, undated
  - Crane, Henry Hitt, 1955-1960, undated
  - Cranks and crackpots, 1955-1956, 1962-1965, undated
  - Cranston, Alan, 1969-1971
  - Cree, Buckert, 1959-1963, undated
  - Crime
    - General, 1953-1982, undated, (4 folders)
    - USSR, undated
    - Washington, D.C., 1968-1971 (Box 84)
  - Crusade against Communism, 1959
  - Crusade for Freedom, 1954-1958
  - Crusader, 1953-1964
  - Cuba, 1959-1977, 1988, undated, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 85)
  - Cultural exchange, 1958-1960
  - Cunningham, Bill, 1949-1959
  - Cupples, Walter W., 1959, undated
  - Cvetic, Matt, 1950-1964, undated
  - Cybernetics, 1953-1967, undated
  - Czechoslovak National Council of America, 1956-1976, (2 folders)
  - Czechoslovakia (Box 86)
    - Ecumenical Council of Churches in Czechoslovakia, 1956-1968, (2 folders)
    - Free Czechoslovak Press, Ltd., 1966-1968
    - General, 1951-1971, 1989, undated, (5 folders)
  - “C” miscellaneous, 1947-1988, 1996, undated, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 87)
  - Dalton, Cornelius, 1946-1958, 1978, undated
  - Dahlberg, Edwin T., 1957-1958, 1986
  - Daily World, 1969-1970, undated
  - Danielopol, Dumitru, 1967-1973, undated, (3 folders)
  - Daniloff, Nicholas S., 1986
  - Dann, Sol A., 1968-1969
  - Dartmouth College, Hanover, N.H., 1963-1967, 1990
  - Dartnell Corp., 1968, undated
  - Daughters of the American Revolution (DAR), 1952-1970, undated
  - David C. Cook Publishing Co., 1961-1962, undated (Box 88)
  - Davenport, Russell W., 1954, undated
  - Davis, Angela, 1970-1980, 1989
  - Davis, Benjamin J., 1935, 1947-1951, 1964
  - Davis, Jerome, 1955-1960, undated
  - Davis, Ossie, 1955, 1962, 1969, undated
  - Dawson, James R., 1967-1969, undated
  - Day, Dorothy, 1965-1966, 1972-1973
  - Day, Gardner M., 1934, 1953-1954
  - Death penalty, 1954-1958, 1972
  - Defectors, 1960-1972, undated
  - Defenders of American Liberties, 1963-1964
  - Defense, 1952, 1966-1976, 1984, undated
  - DeGregory, Hugo, 1956-1966
  - Del Junco, Tirzo, 1961-1963
  - Delaware Valley Coalition, 1965
  - Dellinger, David, 1967-1970
  - Democratic National Convention, Chicago, Ill., 1968-1969
  - Democratic Party, 1964-1967, 1971-1972
  - Demonstrations, 1965-1967
  - Deriabin, Petr S., 1959
  - Deserters, 1968-1970, undated
  - Detente, 1974-1975
  - Detrhi Offset Supplies, 1951-1954, undated
  - Devlin, Bernadette, 1969-1972, undated
  - DeWitt, Robert L., 1967, undated (Box 89)
  - Diamond, J. Robert, 1951, 1958
  - Dictatorship, 1963, 1971
  - Dirksen, Everett M., 1967-1969, undated
  - Disarmament, 1958-1969, 1982
  - District of Columbia Baptist Convention, 1973-1974
  - Djilas, Milovan, 1956-1957, 1970-1973
  - Dobriansky, Lev E., 1963-1967, undated
  - Dodd, Bella, 1963-1969
  - Dodd, Thomas J., 1959-1969, undated, (2 folders)
  - Dohrenwend, Otto, 1953-1969
  - Dominican Republic, 1958-1967
  - Dole, Robert (of Exeter, N.H.), 1963, undated
  - Donati, James E., undated
  - Dondero, George A., 1960, undated
  - Douglas, William O., 1969-1973, undated
  - Dow, Richard, 1963-1967, undated
  - Dr. Fred L. Dunn Ad Hoc Committee, 1971-1972, undated
  - Draft (military), 1965-1973, undated (Box 90)
  - Dresser, Robert B., 1961, 1966-1968
  - Drew, Dorothy, 1956-1958, undated
  - Drugs, 1967-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - Drummond, Roscoe, 1952-1954, 1960-1962
  - DuBois, W. E. B., 1959-1971, undated
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1954-1959